wsp-pb.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy | WSP

WSP Global Inc. and its subsidiaries (“ **WSP** ”) is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of your personal information (“ **Personal Information** ”) and complying with relevant data protection legislation. Please take the time to read this Privacy Policy, as it provides information about the types of Personal Information WSP may collect and how it is used and protected. When reading this Privacy Policy on any of the WSP websites, it should be read in conjunction with WSP’s website Terms of Use.

**Please expand the relevant sections in this Privacy Policy to view information on a particular topic.**

As a global professional services firm, WSP acts as a data controller for the Personal Information provided by clients, business partners, and other individuals, including website users and job applicants who access the WSP “Careers” website (“ **Data Subjects** ”). The details of WSP entities who are data controllers of Personal Information are set out [here](http://cdn.wsp-pb.com/73r13z/wsp-entities.pdf). If you have any questions about the data controller of your Personal Information, please refer to the “Contact us” section below.

The types of Personal Information that WSP collects and processes about you depend on whether you are a potential or existing client or business partner, a WSP website user or an applicant to a position within WSP. Where you provide WSP with Personal Information about other individuals (for example, other people within your organization), please refer them to this Privacy Policy.

**View the categories below to understand how WSP collects and processes your personal Information.**

WSP WEBSITE USERS, OR PERSONS INTERACTING WITH WSP ON SOCIAL MEDIA OR BY EMAIL

**What information may WSP collect?**  
―    Your name.  
―    Company.  
―    Title.  
―    Email address.  
―    Telephone number.  
―    Your IP address.  
―    Information obtained through our use of cookies and widgets.

For more information, please see the WSP Cookie Policy. For more information about cookies in general, click [here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**How will WSP collect your Personal Information?**  
―    Through requests or inquiries to WSP through e-mail, social media sites or affiliated blogs.  
―    Through a subscription to a WSP newsletter, blog or other marketing related messages.  
―    Through your access to WSP websites (cookies may be placed on your computer or mobile device).

**What does WSP use your Personal Information for?**  
WSP uses the Personal Information it is provided with for legitimate business purposes, including marketing its services, engaging in business development activities or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. The following are examples of the ways WSP uses your Personal Information for business purposes:  
―    To answer any inquiries or requests you make.  
―    To further communicate with you on any matter relating to your inquiry or request.  
―    To contact you about other WSP information and services that may be of interest to you. (See section for “Recipients of WSP electronic messages”).

**Who will WSP share your Personal Information with?**  
WSP will not sell, rent or trade your Personal Information to any third party and will only share your Personal Information with:  
―    Other WSP entities.  
―    Third party service providers, who process data on WSP’s behalf or who facilitate or are outsourced one or more aspects of the operation of the websites or the business such as our website providers and IT providers.  
―    Specific third parties in the context of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of WSP assets. In such cases, due notifications, as required by law, will be made.  
―    Third parties where WSP is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process in any country where WSP operates or to conduct any similar sharing permitted by applicable law.

POTENTIAL OR EXISTING CLIENTS OR BUSINESS PARTNERS

**What information may WSP collect?**  
―    Your name.  
―    Title.  
―    Company.  
―    Email address.  
―    Information gathered from public sources such as internet searches.

**How will WSP collect your Personal Information?**  
―    Through requests or inquiries to WSP through e-mail, social media sites or affiliated blogs.  
―    Through a business event or conference.  
―    In person (for example, if you provide your business card to a WSP employee).  
―    Provisions of services for or otherwise contracting with WSP.  
―    Through the development of business partnerships.  
―    At the occasion of visiting WSP offices, facilities or accessing WSP systems.  
―    Through direct contact with WSP by telephone (voice over IP (VOIP) telephones may capture your Personal Information).  
―    From public sources, such as internet searches, your company website and social media sites (such as LinkedIn and Twitter through questions, answers, comments and retweets between you and WSP).

**What does WSP use your Personal Information for?**  
WSP uses the Personal Information it is provided with for legitimate business purposes, including to enter into or perform obligations under the contract WSP holds with you, or to engage with clients and business partners, to deliver its professional services, or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. The following are examples of the ways WSP uses your Personal Information for business purposes:  
―    To provide professional services.  
―    To engage you as a business partner.  
―    To manage WSP’s business relationship with you or your employer.  
―    To comply with legal obligations.  
―    To investigate and prevent fraud or misconduct.  
―    To issue communications or billings around projects, contracts or joint endeavours.  
―    To pursue or contract for work.  
―    To evaluate prospective service providers.  
―    To answer questions and inquiries related to services of either party.  
―    To otherwise conduct everyday business activities, such as business development, business planning, strategic reviews and statistical, evaluation and reporting purposes.  
―    To contact you about other WSP information and services that may be of interest to you. (See section for “Recipients of WSP electronic messages”).

**Who will WSP share your Personal Information with?**  
WSP will not sell, rent or trade your Personal Information to any third party and will only share your Personal Information with:  
―    Other WSP entities.  
―    Specific third parties in the context of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of WSP assets. In such cases, due notifications, as required by law, will be made.  
―    Third party service providers, who process data on WSP’s behalf or who facilitate or are outsourced one or more aspects of the operation of the websites or the business. Third party service providers include IT service providers, lawyers in connection with actual or threatened litigation, and auditors.  
―    WSP business partners who provide services to our clients.  
―    WSP clients where you are a business partner.  
―    Third parties where WSP is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process in any country where WSP operates.  
―    To third parties when it is reasonably believed that disclosure is necessary to protect people’s safety, security, rights or property, or as otherwise permitted by applicable law.  
―    To the police or financial crime and fraud detection agencies to investigate fraud or corruption, or to conduct any similar sharing permitted by applicable law.  
―    To a government entity in response to a government request.  
―    Third parties where WSP is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process in any country where WSP operates.

POTENTIAL OR EXISTING JOB APPLICANTS  
WSP collects and processes your Personal Information when you apply for a job at WSP, including for applications made on the WSP Careers website. In accordance with applicable law, WSP may keep the information you submit in connection with an application for employment and for future consideration.   
****

**What Information may WSP collect?**  
―    Your name.  
―    Address.  
―    Contact details.  
―    Education background.  
―    Employment history.  
―    Reference or results of employment checks.  
―    Your resume (CV).  
―    Information obtained from your cover letter and in the context of your job application.

All information provided in job applications must be accurate and any errors may result in withdrawal of an offer of employment or termination of employment. When applying through WSP Careers webpages, you may delete or change your account by yourself at any time or you may request that WSP do so by sending an e-mail to the Privacy Office.

**How will WSP collect your Personal Information?**  
―    Directly from you when you provide it in your resume (CV) or in the context of a job application.  
―    From WSP Careers webpages.  
―    From references you provide.  
―    From references received from third parties such as education institutions or your current or past employers.  
―    From employment checks, including from publicly available sources, such as Google and LinkedIn.

**What does WSP use your Personal Information for?**  
WSP uses the Personal Information it is provided with for legitimate business purposes, including to enter into an employment relationship with you, and because there is a legitimate business need to assess job applications or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. The following are examples of the ways WSP uses your Personal Information for business purposes:  
―    To consider your application and assess your suitability for the position applied for or for other suitable positions that might match your profile.  
―    To check/obtain information or references about you from third parties.  
―    To inform you of job opportunities, forums, actions or publications that might be of interest to you, as requested.  
―    To review and assess WSP’s hiring policies, practices and statistics.

**Who may WSP share your Personal Information with?**  
WSP will not sell, rent or trade your Personal Information to any third party and will only share your Personal Information with:  
―    Other WSP entities.  
―    Specific third parties in the context of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of WSP assets. In such cases, due notifications, as required by law, will be made.  
―    Third parties contacted by WSP to verify your information and to obtain references such as your previous employers or education institutions.  
―    Third party service providers which WSP uses as part of the job application process. For example, Personal Information collected through WSP Careers webpages will be submitted to and stored on WSP’s behalf by Bell Canada and their partner, Technomedia Training Inc., who provide Human Resources talent management solutions, and to other contracted service providers, as necessary, whose role is to manage or maintain the Personal Information collected in accordance with applicable law. The Bell privacy statement is available for your review here: [Bell Privacy](https://support.bell.ca/Billing-and-Accounts/Security_and_privacy/How_does_Bell_respect_my_privacy#displayStep).  
―    Third parties where WSP is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process in any country where WSP operates, or to conduct any similar sharing permitted by applicable law.

RECIPIENTS OF WSP ELECTRONIC MESSAGES

When you provide contact data to WSP, including through WSP websites, such as name and email address, WSP may send you commercial electronic messages (such as emails) related to its services. If you receive such messages from WSP, you may be in a business relationship with WSP, you may have provided express or implied consent to receive commercial electronic messages from WSP, or the electronic communication may not be subject to legal consent requirements. You may opt out of receiving marketing related electronic messages by clicking on the unsubscribe link contained in the footer of the message or by sending a blank email to [unsubscribe@wsp.com](mailto:unsubscribe@wsp.com). Please note that even if you opt-out of commercial electronic messages, WSP may still need to contact you electronically with information about its business relationship with you, your account or data.

Messages sent by WSP Canadian entities

WSP Canadian entities adhere to the WSP Anti-Spam Commitment. If you are in Canada or if the message is received from a WSP entity operating in Canada, you can further opt-out of receiving marketing related electronic messages by notifying WSP at [unsubscribecanada@wsp.com](mailto:unsubscribecanada@wsp.com). For additional information, contact WSP’s Anti-Spam Compliance Office at [caslcompliance@wsp.com](mailto:caslcompliance@wsp.com). 

WSP operates globally and has worldwide affiliates. When you give WSP your Personal Information, it may be transferred, processed and stored on servers in Canada, where WSP’s head office is located, or in other countries in which WSP operates and therefore, your data may be available to government authorities under lawful orders and laws applicable in such foreign jurisdictions. To that extent, such Personal Information may not be afforded the same protections as under the laws of the jurisdiction in which you reside.

International transfers of Personal Information are subject to appropriate security measures and WSP will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Information is protected and maintained in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable data privacy laws. By providing your Personal Information to WSP you consent to WSP’s transmission to, and processing of, your Personal Information in any jurisdiction.

**European Economic Area and Switzerland (“Europe”)**

Where WSP transfers data collected in Europe to locations outside of Europe, WSP takes the appropriate steps to ensure that your Personal Information is protected, notably by:  
―    Using particular contractual clauses otherwise known as 'standard contractual clauses' which have been approved by the European Commission or through a WSP internal contractual commitment. You can request more details about this by contacting: [privacy@wsp.com](mailto:privacy@wsp.com).  
or  
―    Transferring to countries that have been deemed 'adequate' by the European Commission. This includes Canada as WSP’s headquarters are based in Canada and Personal Information is stored on Canadian Servers. A list of countries deemed “adequate” can be accessed [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).

WSP employs reasonable and customary security measures and technologies to keep your Personal Information secure and protected against loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Where third party vendor organizations process Personal Information on WSP’s behalf (e.g., payroll or outsourcing companies), specific security arrangements will be implemented, when required, through contractual arrangements with those organizations.

WSP may use your email address to contact you about a security incident involving your Personal Information.

E-mail monitoring or blocking software may be used for security purposes and for compliance with WSP policies.

WSP websites may also contain links to other web sites or services which are outside WSP’s control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access or share data to other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect data from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. WSP is not responsible or liable for the privacy standards and practices of third parties. Your use of such websites is at your own risk.

Any information you post or disclose on WSP’s social media or community forums (for example, Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, or other social media applications) is public. WSP cannot control the use of information disclosed in social media platforms or WSP community forums. Exercise caution when disclosing information in public areas, and be careful what Personal Information you disclose and how you disclose it. Content posted in WSP’s community forums, including advice and opinions, represents the views of the individuals who post that content and such individuals bear sole and exclusive responsibility for the posting of that content. WSP does not necessarily endorse, support, verify, or agree with any content posted on our social media or community forums.

Social Media Widgets

WSP websites include social media widgets, such as the Facebook, YouTube, LinkedIn, Instagram, Google + and Twitter buttons and widgets, such as the “Share” button. Social Media widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on WSP’s website. Your interactions with these widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. These widgets may collect your IP address, which WSP webpage you are visiting, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly.

WSP may store your Personal Information in a cloud. This means that your Personal Information may be processed on WSP’s behalf by a cloud provider and could be stored in different locations around the world. WSP makes use of organizational and contractual measures to protect your Personal Information and to impose appropriate security and data protection requirements on our cloud services providers, including the requirement that your Personal Information be processed exclusively for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

WSP uses VOIP technology when you communicate with WSP over the telephone. You can find out more about VOIP [here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voice_over_IP). As your call will be relayed via the internet, WSP cannot control where your data is processed. WSP’s VOIP services are managed by Skype.

WSP retains your Personal Information for no longer than is necessary. WSP will further retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce agreements. For example, WSP usually retains customer information as long as we need to provide services, and for a period of 3 years after the business relationship ends, unless otherwise compelled by the law to retain such information, or in the case of a litigation, or potential litigation.

In accordance with applicable law, you have the following rights, subject to some conditions and exceptions:

―    To object to the processing of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes. To exercise this right, please contact the WSP Privacy Office at any time or, to opt out of commercial electronic messages, click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the message or send a blank email to [unsubscribe@wsp.com](mailto:unsubscribe@wsp.com).  
―    To access a copy of your Personal Information and details about how WSP uses it.  
―    To have your Personal Information corrected or updated.  
―    To request deletion of your Personal Information. If WSP receives such a request, other factors will need to be taken into account when assessing whether to comply.  
―    To request restriction of processing of your Personal Information, for example where you believe that the Personal Information we have about you is inaccurate.

**All requests regarding your Personal Information should be sent to the Privacy Office.**

WSP will respond to such requests within thirty (30) business days of their receipt or within any other delay required or authorized by applicable law. WSP will take reasonable steps to functionally correct or delete your Personal Information from WSP database(s) upon request, although WSP may keep a copy for archival purposes in compliance with applicable laws. Before WSP provides you with any data, corrects any inaccuracies or deletes any data, WSP may request additional information to verify your identity or otherwise help respond to your request.

European Economic Area and Switzerland (“Europe”)

Where you are engaging with a WSP entity in Europe, European data protection laws, including from 25 May 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") and other national data protection legislation in Europe, grant you the following additional rights:  
―    The right to lodge a complaint regarding WSP’s compliance with data protection laws with the appropriate member state data protection regulator.  
―    The right to withdraw consent where WSP relies on consent to process your Personal Information.

WSP complies with this Privacy Policy as well as applicable laws, including the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act and European data protection laws, including from 25 May 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") and other national data protection legislation in Europe.

If you have any questions, complaints or concerns about privacy or the security of your Personal Information, please contact the WSP Privacy Office. Where relevant or required, WSP will collaborate with the appropriate regulatory authorities to resolve any complaints or issues regarding Personal Information.

**Privacy Office:**  
Shoshana Rosenberg, Global Chief Privacy Officer  
WSP, One Penn Plaza, New York, NY, 10119, USA  
Telephone: +1 212 465 5724  
Email: [privacy@wsp.com](mailto:privacy@wsp.com)

WSP may need to make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect any changes in data protection and privacy laws and to update you on WSP's privacy practices.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in May 2018.

The French version and the English version of this Privacy Policy have the same value. In case of any discrepancy between the meanings of any other translated versions of this Privacy Policy, the meaning of the English version shall prevail.
